

RESUME of BROHOMMA NANDO CHOWDHURY

Mobile: 01777707302 E-mail: ratanchowdhury5@gmail.com

Career Summary:

More than 20 years experience of Accounts & Finance Department, expertise in preparing financial statement, monitoring daily cash transactions, developing annual budgets, and recording all financial activities.VAT, Income tax, a remarkable experience of working in accounts department in different origination.

Professional Course:

- ➤ Chartered Accountancy Course completed (C.A C.C). instituted of Chartered Accountants in Bangladesh (ICAB) under Tofayel Ahmed & Co, Chartered Accountants, Dhaka, Bangladesh in 18th August 1995
- > ACCA (Partly completed), Instituted of Chartered University collage, and also running student ACCA, registration number- 341568

Education:

- Masters in Commerce (Management), Dhaka University, in 1992 (2nd Class)
- ➤ Bachelors in commerce, Rajshahi university in 1990(2nd Class)
- ➤ H.S.C, Jessore Board in 1988(2nd Division
- ➤ S.S.C, Jessore Board in 1986 (1st Division)

Professional Experiences:

Associated Builders Corporation Limited (ABC Ltd.)

(Business- Construction, Real Estate & Building Product)Location: ABC House 8, Banani C/A Kemal Ataturk Avenue, Dhaka-1213.

Manager- Accounts (January 2016 to till today):

Responsibility overall Accounts & Income Tax Related work.

Mizan Group (Business- Construction, Real Estate, Tower Manufacture & Trading)Location: House # 53, Road # 04, Block # C, Banani, Dhaka.

Manager Accounts & Finance: (Feb, 2014 to December 2015)

- Supervising and controlling the accounting procedure of the organization
- Developing, Controlling, Implementing and monitoring the group accounts
- Budgeting monitoring and controlling
- > Controlling the procurement and disbursement procedure
- Prepaid of accounts for Income tax.
- Responsibility overall accounts

N.A.Z Bangladesh Ltd. (Business-100% export oriented knit composite)

Manager- Accounts: (June 5,2008 to 31, January 2014)

- Major responsibilities costing for Buyer & Style wise, Material Cost sheet analysis and prepaid profit & Loss calculation for pre-costing & Post Costing.
- Daily financial processing, including monitoring of payroll data, cash receipts, billing disbursements, developed policies and procedures for fiscal management
- Managed regular accounting records

- Controlled the salary disbursement and inventory management (Physical Investigation)
- Handling master L/C & back to Back L/C.

HATIM INDUSTRIES LIMITED- A manufacturing of G.I ,M.S , S.S & FMS Pipe as a ISO Certified Company.

Manager- Accounts & Finance: (January 2004 – May 31 2008)

Responsibilities for over all accounts & Commercial for L/C related work. Maintained Account receivable & Payable Ledger prepaid all type of voucher, checking for all type of voucher (Received & disbursement), handling Director's personal income tax & Company Income tax.

VT CONNECTIONS LIMITED- A JOINT VENTURE COMPANY WITH U.S.A 100% Export for Data entry & Data Processing Company.

Asst. Manager- Accounts: (November 1999 to December 2003)

Responsibilities for over all accounts & Finance, Export invoice prepaid, Salary Disbursement for worker, Bank reconciliation.

KISAN GROUP- A manufacturing of Auto Mobiles, & Trading Concern Business.

Senior Executive - Accounts: (September 1995 to October 1999)

- Responsibilities for over all accounts
- International Tender documents prepaid, and vat return statement submission at Vat office.

Accounting Software:

- Using Accounting software Troyee
- Using Accounting Software Tally . ERP 9
- Using Accounting Software Accord
- Using Accounting Software Quick Book Pro Edition 2003.
- Using BBT Inventory Software

Computer Literacy

Microsoft Word & Excel

Personnel Information:

Name : BROHOMMA NANDO CHOWDHURY
Father's Name : LATE, AMULYA KUMER CHOWDHURY
Mother's Name : LATE, KOMOLA RANI CHOWDHURY

Date of Birth : 23rd February 1970.

Nationality : Bangladeshi (By Birth).

Permanent Address: C/o Amulya Kumer Chowdhury

Nabab seraj udd- dulla Road, Jhenidah-7300

References:

(A)Mr. Tofayel Ahamed FCA
Principal
Tofayel Ahmed & Co.
Chartered Accountants
124/8 Shantinagor, 5th Floor, Dhaka

(B) Humayun Bokhteyar ACPA, FCA
Managing Partner

Bokhteyar Humayun & Co.
Chartered Accountants
42/43, Purana Paltan ,3rd floor, Dhaka.
Mobile: 01713009601.

Signature

.____